<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IntentionallyEmpty on Jeff&#39;s Resume</title>
    <link>https://orangebike.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IntentionallyEmpty on Jeff&#39;s Resume</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 12:23:48 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://orangebike.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kustomize</title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/experiences/kustomize/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/experiences/kustomize/</guid>
      <description>Kustomize is a Go-based open-source cluster configuration management tool for kubernetes.
I founded the project, and have taken it 6500 github stars and 100 contributors so far.
In kubernetes, one declares the state of all cluster objects in files, then applies those files to the cluster, where controllers drive objects to their newly desired states. To change the cluster one edits the files and reapplies them. This creates a new problem: how to manage hundreds of variants of cluster configs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills</title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/personal/skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/personal/skills/</guid>
      <description>Go, Java, C++, javascript (unit testing in all); kubernetes (contributor), GKE, GRPC, bazel, git, linux, etc.
Learning: flutter, reinforcement learning vs control theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/personal/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/personal/projects/</guid>
      <description>mdrip extracts and runs fenced code blocks from markdown, collecting output and reporting errors. This literate programming approach allows tutorials to be tested as part of CI/CD, or conversely, allows e2e tests to be framed as tutorials.
gorepomod helps one deploy multiple Go modules from one repository when the modules are interdependent.
gol_grid is my implementation of Conway&amp;rsquo;s game of life using flutter. Used to learn flutter&amp;rsquo;s BLoc pattern, and test mobile vs web performance of same code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terra Bella</title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/experiences/terrabella/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/experiences/terrabella/</guid>
      <description>Terra Bella (now Planet) is a satellite-based Earth imaging service.
I joined Terra Bella (formerly Skybox) after its acquisition by Google. I owned a Java-based service that produced a satellite command stream based on constraints around imaging and comms opportunities. I also worked on integrating commercial TLE propagation code into Google systems. I worked to improve CI/CD, support rollbacks, conduct post-mortems, etc.
Seeing SkySats 4-7 launch with the team, and later accept our commands, was a highlight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vanadium</title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/experiences/vanadium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/experiences/vanadium/</guid>
      <description>Vanadium lets distributed services find each other, securely communicate, and delegate authority using public-key cryptography.
I contributed to the Go libraries and overall project organization, wrote extensive, tested tutorials, worked closely with UX research to validate our material and built demos. One such demo is volley, a distributed OpenGL app for iOS, Android, OS X, and X11 (linux) written in Go that demonstrates vanadium&amp;rsquo;s cross platform power (code).
Vanadium and kubernetes (k8s) started about the same time, approaching distributed computing from different directions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/personal/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/personal/education/</guid>
      <description>Ph.D. Physics, University of California, San Diego Electron Transfer in Proteins: The Electron Tunneling Matrix. TA for Sally Ride.
M.S. Elect. Engineering, University of Iowa, Iowa City Optical Switching at a Nonlinear Dielectric Interface. TA signal processing and control theory.
B.S. Computer Science University of Iowa, Iowa City Indeterminant Execution in Prolog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helpouts</title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/experiences/helpouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/experiences/helpouts/</guid>
      <description>Google Helpouts was Google&amp;rsquo;s attempt to turn video chat into a small business platform.
I worked on the Android app and the Java-based REST API it talked to, arranged for consumer and provider notifications using Google infra, and did Google search &amp;ldquo;failed query&amp;rdquo; integration that presented a Helpouts onebox, and did user studies at random locations in Palo Alto to test our mobile UX.
This project offered piano lessons, cooking, vacation advice and medical services in one app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aphorisms</title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/personal/aphorisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/personal/aphorisms/</guid>
      <description>Humility, respect and trust are the basis of good engineering.
Culture eats strategy for breakfast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G&#43; Games</title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/experiences/games/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/experiences/games/</guid>
      <description>Google+ Games launched when FarmVille was in the news.
I was TLM, coordinating my team&amp;rsquo;s work with extended teams engaged in various aspects of G+ (API, auth, and privacy). My team built the most complex part of the G+ web client, as it had to mitigate the risk of 3rd party apps to running on Google domains. To do so, we launched the first use of OAuth2 at Google, and the first G+ API endpoints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awards</title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/personal/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/personal/awards/</guid>
      <description>Spot Bonus
 Helpouts launch G+ games launch  Conops Engineer Appreciation: iGoogle
Executive Mgmt Group Impact Award: iGoogle</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misc</title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/personal/misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/personal/misc/</guid>
      <description>Five rides across Iowa with family (because fun). Fifteen years of biking to work (because exercise). Climbed Gannett Peak. Muay Thai student. Passable French. US Citizen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iGoogle</title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/experiences/igoogle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/experiences/igoogle/</guid>
      <description>iGoogle was Google&amp;rsquo;s homepage, and Google&amp;rsquo;s first developer platform (gadget authoring).
Just before the transition to G+, I owned (in a git blame sense) most of the C++ server code for iGoogle. I designed and built its gadget data sharing API, which was also Google&amp;rsquo;s first social API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missle Defense UX</title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/experiences/lincoln/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/experiences/lincoln/</guid>
      <description>The Reagan Test Site in Kwajalein does e2e testing of missile defense systems.
I led a team building UX for the op center shown above. Dozens of Java SWT widgets (e.g., a radar bore-site view of incoming threats) displayed data from radar and optical sensors. We also built a simulator to drive the displays for training.
I introduced iterative test and release cycles to the group, moving from an unpredictable bi-yearly cycle to bi-weekly, increasing confidence in the ability to fix problems and ship features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eidogen</title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/experiences/eidogen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/experiences/eidogen/</guid>
      <description>Eidogen was a protein structure prediction startup. As second employee, I led the team that built eve, a protein fold and gene sequence explorer. I based it on Java3d, which at the time was the best way to integrate OpenGL and Swing widgets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/r/atx1flar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/r/atx1flar/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/r/pltr1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/r/pltr1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/r/t4sla9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/r/t4sla9/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/r/txspacex8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/r/txspacex8/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://orangebike.dev/r/txspacex9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orangebike.dev/r/txspacex9/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
